Have I ever paid attention to
fundamental public freedoms?  I
restored them.  Is there a second to
try never?  Why would you want me, at
67, to start a career as a
dictator?  The general was both very
peculiar
and, when he spoke, very impactful.
I say when he expressed himself because he didn't make
jokes all the time and
in everyday life it wasn't an
issue.  But in the most
unexpected moments, he sometimes had
reactions of a humor that could be
extremely funny and sometimes
extremely ferocious.
1941 in London.  It is from this
period that De Gaulle's relatives and
historians have preserved the general's witty remarks
.  Here are some examples of
De Gaulle's humor.
Two people close to the general discuss and
criticize human folly.
Jean Pompé is written "dead to the [ __ ]".  Corner
de Gaul then enters the office and
drops it.   A
vast program.
June 14, 1944, [music] de Gaulle
lands at Courseul.  One of his
colleagues said to him: "Do you realize,
General, that it was 4 years ago to the
day that the Germans entered
Paris."
Well, they were wrong.
August 1944,
in liberated Cherbourg, de Gaulle receives a
triumphant welcome from the crowd gathered on
the sidewalks when he hears a
high-pitched voice shout "Long live the Marshal!"
Another one who doesn't read the newspapers.
A month later, de Gaulle, visiting
Toulouse, reviewed the
FFI troops where many officers had awarded themselves
higher ranks
which they had sewn onto the
mismatched uniforms.  He passes by a simple
soldier who only has one [music]
string.  The general notices this and
then says, "We don't know how to sew."
In that same year 44, on November 30,
de Gaulle stopped in Stalingrad where he
[music] met Molotov.  Lost in thought, the
general said to him,
"What an army!
Isn't it?"  exclaims [music] the
foreign minister, drunk with
happiness, our great Soviet people.